A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Office of the Secretary of Finance, 1989-2005
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Office of the Secretary of Finance, 1989-2005
The Library of Virginia
43787
7 cu. ft. (7 boxes)
Virginia. Secretary of Finance.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Restricted material has been marked on the finding aid, but has not been removed from the collection. The folders must be reviewed before being served.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Secretary of Finance, 6 June 2008.
Biographical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" to assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties; compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governor's top management team or "secretariats," as they are called now. The General Assembly in 1972 created six Secretariats positions initially. As government reorganized, that number fluctuated when government agencies expanded or consolidated.
Since the establishment of a secretarial system in 1972, there have been several reorganizations of that system. The financial management function of the state has shifted from under the direction of the Secretary of Finance to the Secretary of Administration; then to Secretary of Administration and Finance and currently back to the Secretary of Finance, through various reorganizations of state government from 1970s to the present. The function of the secretary is to provide sound fiscal management and recommend to the Governor a comprehensive budget for those agencies under his jurisdiction. The secretary's responsibilities are: to monitor programs, services and performance of subordinate state agencies to develop state policies programs for long-range planning and policy formulation; and approve solicitation or acceptance of any donations, gifts or grants; to hold agency heads accountable for their agency's administrative, fiscal and program performance. All secretaries are appointed by the governor and serve at his will.
Scope and Content
Records of the Office of the Secretary of Finance from 1989-2005 covering the Gubernatorial Administrations of Gerald Baliles, L. Douglas Wilder, George F. Allen, James S. Gilmore and Mark R. Warner. The records include correspondence, memorandums, presentation, decision briefs, reports and files by subject. Notable subjects include: National Air and Space Museum Expansion, Higher Education Decentralization, Baseball, and Decision Briefs for the Gilmore Administration (1998-2002). THIS COLLECTION HAS NOT BEEN PROCESSED.
Contents List
- Grading of States, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Financial World, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Attachments to Financial World, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Financial World Survey, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Financial World, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Financial World, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Financial World, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- GACRE, 2003 November (Box 1, Folder Binders)
- Virginia Institute of Political Fellows, 1996 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Virginia Institute of Political Leadership, 1994 September 24 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Higher Ed Decentralization Proposals, 1994 (Box 1, Folder Binder)
- Integrated Human Resources Information System, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Land Mobile Radio Network Upgrade, State Police, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Management Standards, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Metro, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- National Air and Space Museum, Memos of Understanding, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- National Air and Space Museum, Extension, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- National Air and Space Museum, Extension, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- National Air and Space Museum, Extension, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- National Air and Space Museum, Extension, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Rating Agencies, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Referenda (Localities), 2002 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Government Performance Project, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Tobacco Securitization, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Trigon Blue Cross-Blue Shield, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Virginia Executive Institute, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Virginia Post-Attack Economic Response Task Force, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Financing, Old State Library and Finance Building, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Tobacco Commission, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Computer Resource Team (DOE), 2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Supplier Diversity Program, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Resumes (MUST BE REVIEWED BEFORE USE), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- VCU Qatar (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Drug Study (Item 266.C), 2000 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Financial World, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Higher Education Decentralization Symposium, 1997 June 20 (Box 3, Folder Binder)
- Higher Education Decentralization Task Force, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Decentralization, 1997 July 24 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Higher Education Decentralization Symposium, 1997 June 20 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Decentralization, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Decentralization, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Decentralization, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Research, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Decentralization, Higher Education, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Decentralization, Higher Education, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Decentralization, Higher Education, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Decentralization, Higher Education, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Decentralization, Higher Education, 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Reports, 1992-2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- "AAA" Bond Rating, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Archives, Allen Administration (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Archives, Wilder Administration (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Baseball, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Baseball, 1996-2000 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Management Standards, 1993-2001 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Completed EBR's, House Bills, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Completed EBR's, Senate Bills, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Decentralization, 2004 FY (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Decentralization, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Decentralization, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Counselor to the Governor (Delegation of Authority), 1997-2002 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- General, Treasury, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- DCAC, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Budget Reductions, General Assembly Correspondence, 2002 October (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Final Report of the Commission of Virginia's State and Local Tax Structure, 2001 June (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Decision Briefs, Administration, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Decision Briefs, Commerce and Trade, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Decision Briefs, Education, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Decision Briefs, Finance, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Decision Briefs, Health and Human Resources, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Decision Briefs, Natural Resources, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Decision Briefs, Public Safety, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Decision Briefs, Technology, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Decision Briefs, Transportation, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Financial Secretariat Appointments, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Bonus (MUST BE REVIEWED BEFORE USE), 2002 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Fixed Assets (Furniture), 1994-2002 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Leave Certifications (MUST BE REVIEWED BEFORE USE), 2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Space Assignment MOU, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Statement of Economic Interest, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Travel Approval, Finance Agencies (MUST BE REVIEWED BEFORE USE), 2000 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Financial Statements, Secretary of Finance, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Accounts, Popular Report, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Dept. of Planning and Budget, Annual Report (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Dept. of Planning and Budget, Jim Cook's Papers (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Court Debt Collections (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Harper (Tax), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- PPP (Tax) (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Sales Tax on Food (Box 7, Folder 14)